bostonscientific.com 2015-03-23

# Privacy Policy | Boston Scientific

This Privacy Policy (Policy) sets forth the Boston Scientific Corporation (BSC, we, or us) policies regarding the collection and use of information relating to the BSC web site (Site) that links to this privacy policy. This policy also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal data and how you can access and update this information. When we refer to BSC, we or us, we mean Boston Scientific Corporation, including our affiliates and subsidiaries. Certain areas of the Site contain information intended only for licensed medical professionals. Accordingly, BSC reserves the right to limit certain areas of the Site to those persons who register and meet the qualifications imposed by us. This Policy addresses our privacy practices relating to general and registered use of our Site by all visitors.

BSC has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and our privacy practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirement](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal data. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the Site that links to this privacy policy. While this Policy does cover mobile sites, the TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile sites or applications. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions.

BSC complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. BSC has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view BSC’s certification, please visit [www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/). Furthermore, Boston Scientific abides by the Generally Accepted Privacy Principles (GAPP), as set forth below:

Generally Accepted Privacy Principles (GAPP):

  * Management. Boston Scientific has a program designed to protect personal data in its possession or control. This is done through a variety of privacy and security policies, processes and procedures. This program is overseen by Boston Scientific's Chief Privacy Officer.
  * Notice. To the extent Boston Scientific collects personal data directly from you, Boston Scientific will ensure that you receive or have access to a notice that describes the privacy practices associated with the collection.
  * Choice and consent. To the extent Boston Scientific collects personal data directly from you, Boston Scientific will inform you about what data handling choices you might have.
  * Collection. Boston Scientific will only collect personal data needed to satisfy business purposes or legal or regulatory requirements.
  * Use, retention, and disposal. Boston Scientific uses personal data for a variety of business purposes, which includes regulatory reporting, quality systems management, customer and technical support, system maintenance, data compilation and analysis, data hosting, event reporting, program analysis and maintenance and other related purposes. Boston Scientific retains personal data for only as long as necessary to fulfill the stated purposes, consistent with applicable data retention schedules and thereafter appropriately disposes of such information.
  * Access. Boston Scientific will provide access, as requested and if feasible, to personal data it might have about you.
  * Disclosure to third parties. Boston Scientific discloses personal data to the participating healthcare providers, regulatory authorities, service providers, etc., in the course of its business. These third parties are required to handle personal data in a confidential manner and to maintain adequate security to protect the information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, and destruction.
  * Security for privacy. Boston Scientific employs administrative, physical, and technical safeguards that reasonably and appropriately protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the personal data that it creates, receives, maintains, or transmits.
  * Quality. Boston Scientific attempts to maintain accurate, complete, and relevant personal data.

##  Web Site Privacy Policy Details 

###  Information We Collect and How We Use It 

Personal data is data that can be used to identify or contact you, such as your name, email address, telephone number or similar information. BSC only collects personal data that you choose to share with us, such as when (1) contacting us via the Site (or requesting information), (2) submitting your resume online in response to a job posting, (3) registering online for an event or course or, (4) upon registration for access to those areas of our Site intended only for licensed medical professionals.

We may also collect the following information from you:

  * Information about your business such as company name, company size, business type
  * Medical condition
  * Demographic information such as age, education, gender, interests and location
  * Contact information such as email address and phone number

We use this information to:

  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Send you product updates
  * Respond to your questions
  * Administer your account
  * Conduct surveys or other research and analysis
  * Send you a newsletter
  * Send you marketing communications
  * Improve our Site and marketing efforts
  * Display content based upon your interests
  * Enable you to post your resume, search job postings, and contact or be contacted by prospective BSC representative or agents

####  Registered Users 

If you are a licensed medical professional, to register, you must provide us with certain personal data which may include your name, profession, email address, postal mail address, title, Medical ID and clinical affiliation. We will use this personal data to review and verify your registration information. We may use your personal data to send periodic transactional, marketing, or promotional notices to you or notify you of any changes to this Policy. You can always opt-out of receiving marketing or promotional communications from us by following the "opt-out" procedures described below or on the specific marketing or promotional message. 

####  Resume Submission 

If your personal data is submitted through the Site when applying for a position with BSC, your personal data will be used solely for the purpose of evaluating and accepting you for the position. We may retain your personal data for a period of time, but only for the purpose of considering your application for current or future positions at BSC or as necessary to comply with the law. This information may be shared within BSC as well as with third parties contracted by us to assist BSC with talent acquisition related activities. 

####  Surveys 

We may provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys on our site. If you participate, we may request certain personal data from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and email address) and demographic information (such as city, state or country). We use this information to understand what type of information visitors look for on the site, whether or not they are able to find it, what additional content would be useful on the site, and other information that can be used to help optimize user experience.

We may use third parties to conduct these surveys or contests. The third party would be prohibited from using our users’ personal data for any purpose inconsistent with the management of such surveys or contests.

####  Testimonials 

With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [webmaster@bostonscientific.com](mailto:webmaster@bostonscientific.com?Subject=Testimonials). 

####  Blogs 

From time to time, the Site may offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at webmaster@bostonscientific.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

####  Contacting BSC 

If you contact BSC via the Site, we will only use your personal data contained in your email to respond to your specific inquiry, request, or comments in the email. We may retain your email for a period of time, but will not use any of your personal data for any purpose other than responding to your email, unless such additional use is required or permitted for us to comply with the law. 

####  General Information and Accuracy 

Any information you provide to BSC must be true, accurate, current, non-misleading, and consistent and relevant for the purpose for which you are providing the information. If you are a registered user, you must have the authority to provide the information submitted to and through the Site, and understand and agree that we may from time to time verify such authority. 

####  Usage Data 

The Site automatically tracks certain information about your behavior while visiting the Site. The information gathered includes the URL from which you accessed this Site, and which URL you visit next. We collect and store this aggregate information in order to measure the Site's performance and improve the Site's design and functionality. We may also share this aggregate information with third parties to illustrate how the Site is used and for other marketing purposes.

If you are a registered user, we may use your Usage Data with or without your personal data, in order to measure the Site's performance and improve the Site's design and functionality. We may share aggregate Usage Data with third parties to illustrate how the Site is used and for other marketing purposes. See also "Cookies", below.

####  Cookies 

BSC uses both "session" and "persistent" cookies on this Site. A cookie is a small piece of information that is sent to your browser and stored in your computer's hard drive. The purpose of a cookie is to remember certain user inputs on the Site. Personalization features also use cookies to identify groups of users and deliver appropriate Site content and services, as well as feedback related to marketing and email campaigns.

Session cookies are temporary bits of information that are erased once you exit your web browser or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies are more permanent bits of information that are placed on the hard drive of your computer and stay there unless you delete the cookie. They store information on your computer for a number of reasons, such as retrieving certain information you have previously provided (i.e., username and password), helping to determine what areas of the Site you find most valuable, and customizing the Site based on your preferences on an ongoing basis. Persistent cookies placed on your computer by this Site may hold personal data, but only if you are a registered user or have otherwise consented to the provision of personal data in accordance with the terms of this Policy. Personal data would be used for things like simplifying the login process or serving personalized content on the site. Otherwise, the Site's server only knows that an unidentified visitor with your cookies has returned to the Site. In addition to customization, persistent cookies will be used to provide you with better service on the Site, to compile and analyze statistics and trends, and to otherwise administer and improve the Site for your use. Subject to applicable law and in accordance with the terms of this Policy, information gathered through the use of persistent cookies on the Site may also be shared with third parties who assist us with the management or optimization of our Sites and the delivery of enhanced user experience.

Cookies do not damage your computer. You can set your browser to notify you when a cookie is being sent to your computer. This will notify you whether or not you are required to accept the cookie in order to view certain Site content, and allows you to decide if you want to accept the cookie or not. You can also set your browser to accept all cookies or to refuse cookies altogether. If you do prevent your computer from accepting cookies, you will still be able to fully access the Site, although you may lose some additional functionality and convenience provided through the use of cookies. To learn more about cookies, please search for "cookie" in the Help portion of your web browser.

####  3rd Party Tracking 

The use of cookies by our third parties is covered by our privacy policy. We may not always have access or control over these cookies, however the third parties act on our behalf. Our third parties use session ID cookies to track certain information about your behavior while visiting the Site, to facilitate surveys, and to identify groups of users and deliver appropriate Site content and services, as well as feedback related to marketing and email campaigns. Our third parties employ clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), images, and scripts that help them better manage Usage Data. We do not tie the information gathered to your personal data. 

####  Social Media Widgets 

Our Site may include widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. This feature may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with this feature are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

####  Clear Gifs 

The Site may also use clear gifs (also known as web beacons) in combination with cookies, in order to help Site operators understand how visitors interact with the Site. A clear gif is typically a transparent graphic image (usually 1 pixel by 1 pixel in size) that is placed on the Site, which allows the Site to measure the actions of a visitor who opens the page that contains the clear gif. BSC uses clear gifs to measure traffic and related behavior, and to improve your experience when visiting the Site. We also use clear gifs to manage the content available on the Site. Clear gifs are not tied to personal data. 

####  Flash LSOs 

We use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences such as volume control, or display content based upon what you view on our site to personalize your visit. Third parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use Flash cookies to collect and store information.

Flash cookies are different from browser cookies. Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies, go to [www.macromedia.com](http://www.macromedia.com/).

####  Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting 

We partner with a third party ad networks to either display advertising on our Site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt out by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

###  Disclosure 

In addition to the disclosures described throughout this Policy, and subject to applicable law, we and our third parties may disclose your personal data:

  * To unaffiliated third parties that are under contract to perform services for or on behalf of BSC. Examples of such services are third parties 1) maintain our computer databases; and 2) perform marketing activities;
  * To other persons as permitted by applicable law or regulation; and
  * To law enforcement personnel and agencies, or as part of a legal process, in order to protect our property or in furtherance of an investigation regarding a breach of the Site rules and policies, unauthorized access to or use of the Site or any other illegal activities.

Any access to such information will be limited to the purpose for which such information was provided to our affiliate, subsidiary or third party. Our affiliates, subsidiaries and third parties may be located throughout the world. Accordingly, information may be sent worldwide to countries which provide varying levels of privacy protection. Nevertheless, the affiliates, subsidiaries and third parties are required to uphold and maintain BSC’s policies with respect to privacy and the treatment of your personal data regardless of their locations or the laws of the countries they are based in.

###  Consent to Processing Outside Home Country 

By using our Site, or providing information to BSC, you understand and unambiguously consent to the collection, use, disclosure and retention of information in the United States and other countries and territories, for the purposes set forth in this Policy. You hereby consent to the collection, use, disclosure and retention by BSC of your personal data as described under this Policy, including but not limited to the transfer of your personal data between BSC's third parties, affiliates and subsidiaries in accordance with this Policy. For further certainty, any consent relating to a right to transfer information referred to in this paragraph shall be deemed to include your consent to the transfer of the applicable personal data to a jurisdiction which may provide a different level of privacy protection than that available in your own country. 

###  Opt-Out Choices 

To "opt-out" of (1) having your Site provided personal data disclosed to third parties for marketing purposes, or (2) any other consent previously granted for a specific purpose concerning your personal data on this Site, send an e-mail to BSC at [webmaster@bostonscientific.com](mailto:webmaster@bostonscientific.com?Subject=Opt-out). To "opt-out" of receiving a particular marketing or promotional communication, follow the unsubscribe instructions included in the specific communication. 

###  Access and Choice 

If you are a registered user or have provided BSC with your personal data, you may request to review, change or delete information previously provided to us by modifying your profile at the Login Screen or by sending an e-mail to [webmaster@bostonscientific.com](mailto:webmaster@bostonscientific.com?Subject=Update%20Personal%20User%20Data). Requests for changes to or deletions of your personal data should be made by you directly. We will respond to all access requests within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will also retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

###  Other Web Sites 

This Policy applies only to BSC Sites that link to this privacy policy. This Site includes links to both our affiliated sites and to non-BSC web sites, including access to content, products and services of such affiliated and non-affiliated sites (Other Sites). In some cases, these Other Sites are made available via "framing technology", and may appear to be part of this Site. However, prior to accessing Other Sites or non-BSC content via the BSC Site, a dialogue box will inform you that you are about to leave the Site, and will prompt you for your consent to proceed. Although some of the entities controlling these framed sites are under contract with BSC, we urge you to familiarize yourself with the individual privacy and other terms for each linked or framed site prior to providing your personal data. All BSC Sites that are governed by this privacy policy will have a link to this document. 

###  Security 

BSC takes seriously the security of the information it collects. BSC has therefore implemented technology and security policies and procedures intended to reduce the risk of accidental destruction or loss, or the unauthorized disclosure or access to, such information, reasonably appropriate to the nature of the data concerned.

When you enter sensitive information (such as personal health information), we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL) We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal data submitted to us through our Sites, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [webmaster@bostonscientific.com](mailto:webmaster@bostonscientific.com?Subject=Security%20Question).

###  Minors 

Our Site is not intended for use by individuals under the age of 18, and BSC does not knowingly collect personal data from those in this age group. If you are under 18, please discontinue the use of our Site. If we become aware that someone under the age of 18 has registered, we will expunge any related personal data from our records. 

###  Updates to Privacy Policy 

BSC may, in its sole discretion, update this Policy at any time and from time to time, by posting the amended Policy on this Site. The amended Policy shall be effective upon posting, and your access to or use of the Site following an update shall be deemed consent to the revised Policy. We urge each visitor to refer back to this page regularly and especially prior to providing or updating any personal data. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. This Policy was last updated on April 30, 2012. 

###  Contact, Questions, Comments, Complaints 

If you would like to communicate with BSC regarding privacy issues or have questions, comments or complaints about this Policy or Site, please contact us using one of the following ways:

Email: [Globalprivacy@bsci.com](mailto:Globalprivacy@bsci.com?Subject=Website%20Privacy%20Question)

Postal Mail:  
Boston Scientific  
Global Compliance – Privacy Office  
4100 Hamline Avenue – Mail Stop 3-302  
Saint Paul, MN 55112 (USA)

If contacting us does not resolve your issue or complaint, you may raise your issue or complaint with TRUSTe by [Internet here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request), or by fax at 1-415-520-3420 or mail to TRUSTe Safe Harbor Compliance Dept., [click for mailing address](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). If you are faxing or mailing TRUSTe to lodge a complaint, you must include the following information: the name of company, the alleged privacy violation, your contact information, and whether you would like the particulars of your complaint shared with the company. For information about TRUSTe or the operation of TRUSTe's dispute resolution process, click [here](http://www.truste.com/why_TRUSTe_privacy_services/online-privacy-watchdog) or request this information from TRUSTe at any of the addresses listed above. The TRUSTe dispute resolution process shall be conducted in English. For human resources data we have agreed to cooperate with Data Protection Authorities.

__ Top
